# Addison Okell

#### **SUMMARY**

Third year Mathematical Physics student from the University of Waterloo, with three terms of term distinction and one term of deans, honour roll. Excellent analytical skills and experience using Python, Maple, R and LaTex. Experience researching in an academic environment and a member of the Rocketry club. An interest in Theoretical Physics and Mathematics.

### **EDUCATION**

## University of Waterloo

Bachelor of Science, Mathematical Physics - Major Average - 83.0%

 $09\ 2019-04\ 2024$ 

Waterloo, Ontario

## RELEVANT COURSEWORK

- Quantum Mechanics I
- Electricity and Magnetism I & II
- Computational Physics
- I & II
- Classical Mechanics I & II
- Thermodynamics
- Calculus I-III
- Vector Calculus
- Linear Algebra I & II
- ODE I & II
- Statistics I & II

## RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

# University of Waterloo - Faculty of Engineering

 $\underline{Research\ Assistant}$ 

 $01\ 2022-04\ 2022$ 

Waterloo, Ontario

- Researching besetting incidents of ships
- Running ice simulations
- Reading remote sensing and satellite data
- Creating plots of the data using Python

# **Evolution Mining**

Student Lab Technician

 $05\ 2022-08\ 2022$ 

Red Lake, Ontario

- Create a tool in Excel to report accuracy of result
- Write a report on the created tool
- Run assays to find metal content of samples using atomic absorption spectroscopy

## TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: Python, R, LaTex, Maple

Python Libraries: Matplotlib, Numpy, Pandas, netCDF4

Developer Tools: Anaconda, Jupiter Notebook, Spyder, R Studio, Overleaf, TeXStudio, Maple

Technologies/Frameworks: Linux, Windows, MacOS

#### **AWARDS**

- Term Distinction 84.6%
- Term Distinction 86.0%
- Term Distinction 90.5%
- Term Deans Honors List 82.5%
- University of Waterloo Merit Scholarship

## **EXTRACURRICULAR**

# **UW Rocketry Club**

09 2022 - Present

- Analysis for handles for kismet injector valve
- Machining brace for actuation mechanism
- Repairing leaks in valves
- Sourcing parts